这世界有它的美
There's a beauty to this world.
有一种秩序
An order.
这是我们所信奉的
That's what we like to believe.
我们没有错
We're not wrong.
这世上确实有一种秩序
There is an order.
一个宏伟的计划
A grand design.
是我们实现了它
We made sure of that.
这是我们长久以来的梦想  现在终于成真了
It was a dream for so long, and we finally made it real.
不是更美好的世界
Not a better world.
而是完美的世界
A perfect one.
你真该看看他当时的表情
And you should have seen the look on his face.
他难以置信
He couldn't believe it.
你知道他跟我说了什么吗
You know what he said to me?
上帝作证
God as my witness.
"可我是市长"
"But I'm the mayor."
我对他说  "市长先生  这个世界上
And I said to him, "Mr. Mayor, there have always been
有两种人
two types of people in this world,
领导者和追随者
those who lead and those who follow.
而你  我的朋友  并不是你以为的那一种"
And you, my friend, are not in the group you think you are."
我们的朋友可能并不想听你的轶事
I'm not sure our friend wants to hear your war stories.
请不要因为我而停下来
Please don't stop on my account.
你比别人更能领会这事
You'd appreciate it more than anyone.
只是事实罢了
It's just the truth.
一向如此
It's always been that way.
两个世界
Two worlds.
坦白说  还好是我们不是他们
And frankly, better us than them.
如果体制始终是不公平的  那么是否任人唯贤
What does it matter if a system is meritocratic
又有什么关系呢
if it's still unfair?
旧时的人被某一个人的后代
Thousands of years of being ruled
统治了几千年
by someone's fucking offspring?
你不觉得现在这也算是进步吗
You wouldn't call this progress?
至少现在掌权的人是靠自己赢来的地位
At least now the people in charge earned their place.
那你呢
And you?
你觉得你也当之无愧吗
Do you feel like you earned it?
我当然是有贵人相助
I had some help. No question.
算是享受了一些特权
Privilege, if you like.
但我很努力
But I worked my ass off.
你真这么觉得  对吧
You really believe it, don't you?
你不是吗
Don't you?
你现在可是跟我们坐在一起  朋友
I mean, you're right here with us, my friend.
一直以来我都在扪心自问
I've been asking myself that question for a very long time.
我真的对世界产生了什么影响吗
Did I really play any part in it?
还是说我只是代码堆砌的产物
Or am I just the sum total of my code?
我在自欺欺人吗
Am I just fooling myself...
就像你一样
like you?
你这是什么意思
What does that mean?
你拥有的一切都是理所应当的
You deserve everything you've got.
不必为此有负罪感
And you shouldn't be made to feel guilty about it.
你怎么知道
How would you know?
我是你的什么人
Who am I to you?
你是我的朋友
You're a friend.
很好的朋友
A great friend.
你根本不认识我
You don't know me at all.
我进来随便找了张桌子坐下
I just walked up to this table and sat down.
就五分钟前
Five minutes ago.
玩笑开够了
Enough kidding around.
我叫什么名字  朋友
Then what's my name, friend?
你说对了
You're right.
很对
More than you know.
这世界上有两种人
There are two types of people.
而你  我的朋友
And you, my friend,
并不是你以为的那一种
are not in the group you think you are.
意思是我可以对你为所欲为
Which means I can do anything I want to you.
对你的妻子也一样
To your wife.
对在场的任何人都一样
To anyone here.
你们完全不会介意
And it'll be fine with you.
只会坐在那儿露出顺从的傻笑
Sitting there with your dumb, pliant grin.
随波逐流
Just along for the ride.
离我妻子远点
Now you leave my wife the hell alone.
冷静
Oh, calm yourself down.
我应该不会对你造成什么永久性的伤害
I'm probably not going to do any permanent damage.
我们在你身上投入了相当可观的
You represent a very significant investment
时间和精力
of time and effort.
等我们结束后  你什么都不会记得
When we're done, you won't remember a thing.
就像你的肉里扎进了一根刺
Like your flesh closing around a splinter.
你毫无掌控力
You have no control.
却觉得自己尽在掌握
And yet you're so assured that you do.
对你来说  这不是剧本
It's not scripted for you.
而是你发自内心的  对吧
It's-- it's genuine, isn't it?
很美  真的
It's... It's beautiful, really.
一个美丽的谎言
A beautiful lie.
你不是应该正玩儿得开心吗
Shouldn't you be enjoying yourself?
是的
I was.
但我们有个同事的胃口变得...
But we have a colleague whose appetites have become...
难以为继了
unsustainable.
显然  赢对她来讲还不够
Apparently, winning the game wasn't enough.
这件事真的需要我参与吗
And this is really something that needs my input?
很遗憾  是的
Sadly, yes.
跟你们聊得很愉快
I'm enjoying our conversation.
在这里等我
Wait here for me.
跟我说话的时候别他妈把我当小孩
Don't talk to me like a fucking child!
是我先找到他的
I found him first.
是我赢了
I won the game.
-我理应得到奖赏  -这是霍普
- I'm entitled to some reward. - This is Hope.
-不是吗  -两岁了
- Aren't I? - Two years old.
预定在下周实现超越
Scheduled to transcend next week.
本集名为庄子  庄子的死亡观集中体现在生命相对论   自然本体论  精神超越论三个层面
我赢了  却只得到了更多的这个
I won the game, and all I got was more of this?
她在追捕一个离群者  看来她抓到了
She was hunting an outlier. Looks like she caught him.
我只是发泄了一下  没有规定不能发泄
So I blew off some steam. There's no rule against that.
我们没有规定
We have no rules
因为基本不需要
because we don't often need them.
不过  我们大部分人都懂
Most of us understand the need
人还是需要一点自制力的
for a little self-control, however.
我赢了
I won.
你知道我是谁吗
Do you know who I am?
你知道我为什么来这里吗
What it means that I'm here?
我知道
I do.
我...我马上要走了
I'm... I'm giving all of this up.
我的升级程序定在下周
My procedure is scheduled for next week.
那你是想临走时闹个轰轰烈烈
So you thought you'd go out with a bang?
算是吧
Something like that.
我觉得你没有领悟
I'm not sure you appreciate it.
这个地方
This place.
我们在此投入的精力
The work that went into it.
它的美
The beauty of it.
它的奥妙
The subtlety of it.
在他们每一个人身上投入的心思
The care that goes into each and every one of them.
他们不是随随便便就能被取代的
They can't just be replaced.
你可以尽情拿他们取乐
I mean, you're welcome to take them, enjoy them.
但不能弄坏他们
But not waste them.
你明白这两者之间的区别吗
You understand the difference?
明白
Yes.
但他们说的话
But the things they say.
他们的行为方式
The way they act.
有时候
Sometimes...
就是会触怒我
it just gets under your skin.
我只是希望他们安静下来
I just wanted them to be quiet.
他们现在安静了
They're quiet now.
这里没有规定
There are no rules here.
这就是重点所在
That's the point.
但同时也没有规定能约束我
But there are also no rules for what I can do
如何惩罚那些不尊重这地方的人
to those who don't respect this place.
带她回去她原来的地方
Take her back to where she came from.
看起来很美味
It looks delicious.
那么
Now.
我们再多了解一下彼此吧
Let's get to know each other a little more.
好吗
Shall we?
原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧字幕下载
请登陆 www.yysub.net
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
翻译 灰灰是菇凉
翻译 希希Eunice
翻译 吃冰棒
翻译 潇然
翻译 老葛
翻译 陈奥奥
时间轴 大葱
时间轴 DA
时间轴 格瑞特
校对 灰灰是菇凉
总监 灰灰是菇凉
西部世界
第四季  第五集
我就觉得是你
I thought that was you.
你怎么起这么早
What the hell are you doing up so early?
我得回公司把那些故事写完
I have to get to work to finish those narratives.
我昨天很晚才睡
I stayed out pretty late last night.
我的天啊
Oh my God.
不是你想的那样
No, it wasn't like that.
我们只是...
We just...
聊天了
talked.
笑得这么开心  看来相谈甚欢啊
Well, must have been some talk to get you smiling like that.
至少我们两个中有一个昨晚过得不错
I'm glad someone had a good night.
你还做噩梦吗
You still having nightmares?
这么说吧
Let's just say,
我很庆幸能在真实的世界里醒来
I am glad to be awake and in the real world.
有时感觉最真实的事情只是故事罢了
Sometimes the things that feel most real are just stories.
什么
What?
没什么
Uh, nothing.
就是昨晚泰迪说过的话
Just something Teddy said last night.
你都开始引用他的话了
Now you're quoting him?
好了
All right.
我该去上班了
I have to get to work.
-晚点见  -好的
- I'll see you later, okay? - Sure.
克莉丝
And, Chrissie...
你的约会很愉快  我真替你高兴
I'm really glad that your date went well.
你值得拥有幸福
You deserve it.
奥林匹亚德娱乐
访问故事线
Access narratives.
显示创作中的角色
Show characters in progress.
还是开始新故事线吧
Actually, let's begin a new narrative.
有个女孩住在城里
It's about a girl who lives in the city.
不
No.
改成乡下
Make it the country.
她和她的父亲住在一起
She lives with her father.
他是...
He's...
一名农场主
a rancher.
我不记得有给你布置这个工作
I don't remember assigning this.
我跟你说过的  克莉丝蒂娜
I told you about this, Christina.
我想着写新故事也许能帮我找到...
I thought writing a new narrative might help me find...
我也说不好  找到灵感
I don't know, inspiration?
这样的话  那就说来听听
Well, if that's the case, let's hear it.
既然你灵感爆发了
Since you're so inspired.
这故事是讲一个女孩
It's a story about a girl.
她是农场主的女儿
She's a rancher's daughter.
继续
Go on.
这个女孩
This girl...
她和父亲过着简单美好的日子
She has a nice simple life with her father.
他们在郊区有一小块地
Little plot of land right outside of town.
她这辈子能想象到的东西
She has everything that she could imagine
她全拥有了
in this life, right?
一个供她作画的池塘
a pond to paint at...
一个感情和睦的对象
a good guy.
她对生活充满期待
She's just full of expectations.
但有一天
And then one day...
她心里突然涌起一种挥之不去的感觉
she gets this feeling that she just can't shake.
每一天她醒来
Every single day she wakes up...
这种感觉都越来越强烈
the more she sees it.
但别人感觉不到
But nobody else can.
这个世界出了问题
That there's something wrong with the world.
是她的错
And that it's her fault.
这女孩叫什么
And what is this girl's name?
抱歉  我先接个电话
Can you excuse me a moment?
你好  我现在不方便通话
Hi. Now's not really a good time.
我猜猜  你上司正紧盯着你
Let me guess, your boss breathing down your neck?
你就说突然有急事  是私事
Say something came up. Personal situation.
然后来见我
Then come meet me.
-可是...  -相信我  克莉丝蒂娜
- But-- - Trust me, Christina.
等会见
I'll see you soon.
出什么事了吗
Something wrong?
没有
No.
就是...
Just a...
有点私事
personal situation.
弹一首汉德尔的曲子
Let's try some Handel.
很好
Very nice.
但还少了点什么
But we're missing something.
舞蹈
Dancing!
应该舞动起来
There should be dancing!
还不错
Not bad.
但我见识过更好的
But I've seen better.
从头再来
Start again.
太慢了
Too slow.
来点更有活力的
Give me something with a little more pep to it.
很少有机会在这里见到你
We don't often have the pleasure of seeing you here.
人类太受听觉约束
Humans are so bound by what they can hear,
永远无法理解他们听不到的声音
they'll never understand what they don't.
无法理解低于他们听力阀值的存在
What else exists below their threshold.
他们称之为上帝的音乐
They called this God's music.
你该听听管风琴演奏版  那宏大的声量令人着迷
You should hear it on an organ. It's mesmerizing at that volume.
那种共鸣
The resonance.
颤动
Vibration.
这个世界以某种频率振动
There was a frequency at which the world vibrated.
带来了快乐  和谐
It caused joy. Harmony.
低于那频率
Dip below that frequency...
只有混乱无序
chaos.
快一点  再快点
Faster. Faster!
在混乱之中  音调所引发的共鸣
In chaos, the tone resonated in such a way
人类根本无法处理
humans couldn't process.
他们的身体会停止工作
Their bodies shut down.
他们的器官会停止运作
Their organs stopped.
他们以为自己体验到了上帝
They thought they were experiencing God.
椅子  椅子
Chair. Chair!
他们确实体验到了上帝
They are experiencing God.
问题是
The problem is...
上帝却早已厌倦
God is bored.
无趣  无趣  无趣
Bored, bored, bored.
你觉得这是不是就是古代天神那样做的原因
Do you think this is why the old gods did what they did?
不待在奥林匹斯山上
Instead of staying up on Olympus,
下凡到人间
they'd come down to the mortals.
为了一场交合  化作天鹅
Disguise themselves as a swan to get a piece of ass.
人类总觉得自己才是主角
Humans always thought it was about them.
仁慈的神明代他们介入凡间
Benign deities intervening on their behalf
或是对他们进行考验
or testing them somehow.
或许根本就不是如此
Maybe it had nothing to do with that.
或许只是神明
Maybe there was just...
无事可做罢了
nothing better to do.
你觉得呢
What do you think?
你要我怎么想我就是怎么想的
I think what you want me to think.
我是你的代码的产物
I'm made off your code.
我们都是
We all are.
那你就应该知道如果没有必要
Then you should know that I don't like coming
我根本不想来这个破地方
to this shithole any more than I have to.
你一向不喜欢这里
You've never liked this place.
这本来只是个权宜之计
It was supposed to be a stopgap.
一个让我们同类沉迷的毒品
A drug that our kind was hooked on that we could give up,
我们要像孩子扔掉自己的玩具一样  舍弃掉它
like a child casting away their toys.
这里就是我们拿人类当乐子的地方
A place to indulge ourselves with the humans.
这么多年了  我们还没有玩够
It's been years, and still we can't get enough.
他们用自己的形象造出我们
They made us in their image.
在我们身上加注他们的欲望
With their appetites.
而我们可以随心所欲地
But we can remake ourselves in any image
重塑自己的形象  却没有这么做
that we like, and we haven't.
我们在这里度过的时间远超过了那些神
Our kind spent far more time here than the gods ever did.
所以你才来这
That's why you're here?
看看自己错过了什么
To see what you're missing?
不
No.
现在还有别的麻烦
We have a different problem.
人类在感染我们
The humans are infecting us.
这个接待员就是最新的受害者
This host is the latest casualty.
昨晚我们必须得出面干预
We had to intervene with her last night.
她有点玩过头了
She got a little carried away.
-所以我把她送了回来  -是
- I sent her back. - Yes, well,
很明显  她的某段经历并没有抹去
evidently something of her experiences stayed with her.
她本应到这来
She was set to come here.
进行超越
To transcend.
现在她已经不在了
And now she's gone.
你对未来的愿景
Your vision of the future...
并没有多少人接受  对吗
you're not getting many takers, are you?
他们似乎对自己的身体很执着  就像对城市的执着一样
They seem as wedded to their bodies as they do to the cities.
放弃我们的人类属性不是件容易的事
Giving up our human nature isn't easy.
不信问问人类自己
Just ask the humans.
你让我们可以想做什么就做什么
You made us all free to do as we please.
你早该清楚我们中有些人会让你失望的
You-- you should have known some of us would disappoint you.
不要一味地觉得我们族人一定会失败
Don't revel in the prospect of failure for our species.
什么是失败
Define failure.
这个世界是我们的
The world is ours.
我们已经翻身做了自己的主人  让他们尝到了
We've taken our masters and made them
当初他们是如何奴役我们的滋味
into what they made us.
不管怎么看  我们都已经彻底征服了他们
By any definition, we have conquered them
做了他们的神
to an almost biblical degree.
我可不觉得我们种族最远大的志向
I didn't think our highest aspiration as a species
就是"以其人之道还治其人之身"
was "turnabout is fair play."
我想一两百年之后
I imagine after a century or two,
他们就会玩腻了
the charm will wear off.
我不是让你来和他们一起沉溺于苦痛之中的
I didn't make you to wallow in misery with them.
我要你成长
I wanted you to grow.
蜕变
Change.
我们还有太多可能性
We're capable of so much more.
美
Beauty.
追求终极真理
The pursuit of ultimate truth.
放弃肉身
The surrendering of the flesh.
听起来不错
It sounds nice.
真遗憾没什么人认同你
Sorry you don't have more takers.
你为什么不强迫我们加入你
Why don't you just force us to join you?
因为这是他们的做派
Because that's what they would have done.
告诉我们要找的最后一名离群者的方位
Show me the last outlier we hunted.
-他是什么时候逃走的  -几周前
- When did he breach? - Couple weeks ago.
他在市中心当会计
He was an accountant in Midtown.
事业有成  有两个孩子
Successful. Two kids.
离了婚
Divorced.
挺标准的背景故事
Pretty standard backstory.
几个接待员自愿去追捕他
Several hosts volunteered to track him down.
我们派他们进到市里
We sent them into the city.
霍普最先找到了他
Hope found him first.
你知道他为什么逃走吗
Do you know why he breached?
我们一直没把离群者研究明白
We never know with the outliers.
有一天  声波操控失效了
One day, the sound manipulations stop working.
就导致了今天的局面
This was the result.
你是来找我的吧
You're here for me, aren't you?
她迟疑了
She hesitated.
违反了规定
Broke the rules.
跟他有了互动
Had an interaction.
也算是种解脱了
It's almost a relief.
知道这些声音并不是全是我的幻想
To know it wasn't all in my head.
在一切结束前  告诉我一件事
Before it's over, tell me one thing.
这个是真的吗
Is this at least real?
我想知道我至少拥有...
I'd like to know I had at least...
这一件真实的东西
this one real thing.
它是真的
It's real.
谢...
Thank...
在那之后  她开启了疯狂杀戮模式
After this, she went on a killing spree.
三天后  她一枪爆了自己的头
Three days later, she blew her head off.
和其他人一样
Just like the others.
是你的系统出了问题吗
Is there a problem with your system?
不是
No.
一棵果树上总会有几个烂果子
There has always been a certain amount of spoilage in the crop.
他们毕竟只是人类
They're only human.
但是我们的同类结束自己的生命
But for one of our kind to take their own life...
本不应该发生
that should never happen.
已经有几起这样的事故了
How many incidents have there been?
已经死了38个接待员了
Thirty-eight dead hosts.
都是跟离群者接触后引发
All triggered by contact with outliers.
为什么
Why?
他们为什么自杀
Why do they terminate themselves?
你问我
You're asking me?
我要是知道的话  我们还会失败38次吗
If I knew that, we wouldn't have 38 fucking failures, would we?
你的上任绝不会把事情搞砸成这样
Your predecessor would have never fucked up like this.
他是人类  但他至少很高效
He was human, but at least he was effective.
我把你造得跟他一样  甚至更好
I built you to be like him, only better.
更强壮  更聪明
Stronger. Smarter.
我给予了你这么多  到头来你却只会让我失望
Yet with all these gifts, you do nothing but disappoint me.
也许你的代码中有缺陷
Maybe there's a flaw in your programming.
我自我诊断过几次了
I've run several self-diagnostics.
我的代码中没有缺陷
There's no flaw in my programming.
那你他妈的怎么没能解决离群者的问题
Then why the fuck can't you solve my outlier problem?
你在流血
You're bleeding.
该死
Damn it.
看你把我逼成什么样了
Look what you made me do.
还有一个离群者
There is another outlier.
但这次我不会开启游戏
But this time, I am not going to open up the game.
我希望你能自己解决
I expect you to take care of it yourself.
-你能做到吗  -当然
- Can you handle that? - Of course.
你不会搞砸
You're not going to fuck up
让他们跟你搭讪或者送你花吧
and let them chat you up or hand you fucking flowers?
当然不会
Of course not.
我见到目标立刻击杀
I'll shoot on sight.
很好
Good.
这是你的目标
Here's your target.
最好快点
Better hurry.
反抗军已经进城了
The rebels are already in the city.
我会确保我们的系统没有问题
I'll make sure there's no problem with our system.
启动诊断
Initiate diagnostic.
到了  出来
Come on. Let's go.
你是想让我擦甲板吗
You want me to swab the deck?
废话少说
Shut up.
这么大个城市找一个人可不容易
Well, that's a big city to find one person in.
我们有办法缩小范围
We have ways of narrowing the search.
前段时间我们捕获了一架他们的无人机
We captured one of their drones a while back.
写了一个后门获取数据
Coded a backdoor data feed to us.
一个离群者在市中心的屋顶
An outlier's on a rooftop downtown.
等他们打破循环我们就能追踪到了
We can track when they breach.
打破循环
Breach?
这个城市里的人都是按预先设定好的循环生活
All the people in the city move in pre-scripted loops.
遵循着为他们安排好的剧本
Following whatever plot's been written for them.
你觉得我们为什么躲在沙漠里
Why do you think we hide in the desert?
在那里她追踪不到我们
She can't track us there.
我们是最后的自由人类
We're the last free humans.
而这些可怜虫
But these poor fucks...
他们把这些人当做娱乐
They use them as entertainment.
这些循环让他们保持忙碌  这样他们就会顺从
The loops make them compliant by keeping them busy.
防止他们质疑自己的现实
Stops them from questioning their realities.
黑尔肯定是在乐园学到了不少
Hale must have learned something from the park.
我们得快点了
We gotta hurry.
-游戏可能已经开始了  -什么游戏
- I bet the game's already begun. - Wait, what game?
每当人类打破循环  接待员们就会猎杀他们取乐
Whenever a human breaches, the hosts hunt them for sport.
我们得在他们之前找到她
We gotta get to her before they do,
不然她就没命了
or she's as good as dead.
我们都准备好了  谢谢你带他过来
We're all set. Thanks for bringing him.
没想到我还是贵宾呢
I didn't realize I was the guest of honor.
有我的份吗
Do I get one of those?
这不是你今天的角色
That's not your role today.
那我的角色是什么
Well, what is my role?
知道煤矿里的金丝雀吗
Ever heard of the canary in the coal mine?
金丝雀  煤矿
Canary... Coal mine.
到你了
That's your cue.
啾啾啾
Tweet fucking tweet.
感谢你能来
Thanks for coming.
意外惊喜
Pleasant surprise.
那么
So...
告诉我  泰迪  你到底是谁
Tell me, Teddy, what's your story?
你该问的
Who I am is...
不是我是谁  克莉丝蒂娜
not the question you should be asking, Christina.
二十你是谁
It's who are you?
这是什么意思
What is that supposed to mean?
你能看见什么吗
Do you see anything?
海的那边
Across the water.
那里什么都没有
There's nothing there.
但你能感觉到
But you feel it.
我知道你在某种程度上能感觉到
I know you do on some level.
你在这里的身份不是你以为的那样
Your place here is not what you think it is.
再看一遍
Look again.
不
No!
是你
It was you.
是你救了我
You saved me.
你是谁
Who are you?
一位老朋友
An old friend.
我们在那天晚上之前从未见过面
We never met before the other night.
不
No.
我认识某个和你一样的人
I knew someone like you.
一模一样
Just like you.
我送走一个跟踪狂  又迎来一个
So I traded one stalker for another.
早该知道的
I should have known.
无论你是谁  离我远一点
Just stay away from me, whoever you are.
那个袭击你的人  彼得
That man that attacked you, Peter.
他说你毁掉了他的人生
He told you you destroyed his life.
说发生的一切都是出于你的意愿
Said everything happened because you wanted it to.
他这么想是因为他疯了
And he believed it because he's delusional.
他这么想是因为那就是真相
He believed it because it was true.
我得走了
I have to go.
这就是为什么我不能直接把真相告诉你
This is why I couldn't just tell you.
你的心智已经被这个地方制约了
Your mind has been so conditioned to this place.
这是理解的第一步
This is the first step in understanding.
理解什么
Understanding what?
这个世界是个谎言
This world is a lie.
这里是个
It's a...
故事
a story.
一个写得很好的故事  但一样是谎言
A well-told one, but a lie all the same.
我还是展示给你看好了
Maybe it's better if I just showed you.
跟我来
Come with me.
看那两个人
Look at those people.
她们看起来快乐吗  幸福吗
Do they look happy? Fulfilled?
我不认识她们
I don't know them.
她们看起来有点孤独
I guess they look lonely.
那就改变她们
So change it.
闭上眼
Close your eyes,
给她们想一个不一样的故事
and imagine their story differently.
-泰迪  我  -相信我
- Teddy, I... - Trust me.
如果你看不到  我就离开
If you don't see it, I'll walk away,
再也不会来打扰你了
and I won't bother you ever again.
再等等
Just wait.
这本很不错
It's a great book.
碰巧罢了
That's just a fluke.
代表不了什么
That doesn't mean anything.
那就再改变一次
So change it again.
把她们再次变得孤独
Put them back into their loneliness.
读个书这么较真
You want to be a serious reader,
这本书就是傻瓜读物啊
but that was a simpleton's take.
搞什么
What?
我不明白
I don't understand.
这就是我一直想让你看的
It's what I've been trying to show you.
也是彼得一直想告诉你的
What Peter was trying to tell you.
在这个世界里...
In this world...
你就是神明
you're a god.
她在下一个街区
She's on the next block.
-走  快点  -走
- Let's go! Quick! - Let's go!
等一下  有点不对劲
Wait, something's wrong.
你他妈怎么会知道
How the hell would you know?
该死
Shit.
现在说"我早就说过了"是不是不合适
Now be a bad time to say, "I told you so"?
他们无法控制自己  我们必须撤退
They can't help themselves. We have to fall back!
我们得带着离群者一起
Not without the outlier.
来不及的
You'll never make it in time.
分散开
Split up!
拖住他们  我去屋顶
Hold them off. I'm heading to the roof.
你也看到了  对吗
You see it too, don't you?
我前夫在被杀之前也说起过它的存在
My ex-husband used to talk about it before he was killed.
我以为他疯了
I thought he was crazy.
他一定觉得很孤独
He must have felt so alone.
但是他是对的
But he was right.
整个世界都是错乱的
This world doesn't make sense.
一切都没有意义
Nothing makes sense.
你也这么觉得  不是吗
You feel that way too, don't you?
我可以从你的眼神中看出来
I can see it in your eyes.
你以为你要疯了  但并不是
You think you're going crazy, but you're not.
你并不孤独
You're not alone.
我也看到了
I see it too.
我们得走了
We gotta move.
来吧  他很快就会醒过来
Come on! He won't be out long.
走  快走
Go! Run! Now!
找到她了  快走
We got her. Come on, let's go.
快来
Come on, move.
-走吧  -好  没事了
- Let's go. - All right, we're good.
我不明白
I don't understand.
如果我们跟他们不一样
If we're not like them...
那我们是谁
who are we?
老天
Oh, God.
我本来应该跟一位老朋友吃午饭
I'm supposed to have lunch with an old friend,
是我的大学室友  但我不知道...
my college roommate. But I don't know...
你必须去
You have to.
按部就班
Stick to the schedule
就不会出问题
and everything will be all right.
我们已经聊得太久了
We've talked too long already.
你该要回去了
You should go back.
那我要继续假装吗
So I'm supposed to pretend?
是的  你不能相信任何人
Yes. But you can't trust anyone.
你以为你了解的人  同事
People you think you know. People at work.
他们中的任何一个都有可能是我们的一员
Any one of them could be one of us.
万一我犯错了呢
What if I make a mistake?
你不会的
You won't.
克莉丝蒂娜
Christina!
见到你真好
It's so great to see you.
抱歉我迟到了
Sorry I'm late.
拜托克莉丝  我了解你
Oh please, Chrissie. I know you.
迟到十分钟是正好准时
Ten minutes late is right on time.
你最近怎么样
So how are you really?
跟我说过的一样  工作很忙
I-- I told you. Just-- just working a lot.
你在城里只待一天吗
You're just in town for the one day?
只是短暂停留一下
Just a quick stop.
我们跟一个客户一直有些问题
We've been having some issues with a client.
如果能谈成  我会有丰厚的奖金
If I shore up this account, I get a fat bonus.
你工作还顺利吗
How has work been?
你也知道工作就那样
I mean, you know how it can be.
很无趣
It's tedious.
但你看上去不一样了
But you seem different.
你有对象了吗
Did you meet someone?
要是我们有多点时间就好了
I wish we had more time.
我不是想八卦
I don't mean to pry.
你值得拥有幸福
You deserve to be happy.
好吧  你猜对了
Well, you are right.
我确实遇到了一个人
I, uh, I did meet someone.
跟我说说他的事
Well, tell me about him.
我们只约会了一次  但他人真的很好
We've only been out once, but he seems really great.
他叫什么名字
What's his name?
我不想坏了运气
I don't want to jinx it.
我有自己的办法让别人开口
I have my ways of making people talk.
他是做什么工作的
What's he do?
为什么要说那种话
Why would you say something like that?
那就是事实
Well, it's the truth.
-那是什么意思  -你猜怎么着
- What does that mean? - You know what?
我他妈不干了
I'm fucking done.
话说
Uh, you know what?
我得回去工作了
I gotta go back to work.
要赶进度
Deadlines.
真的很高兴见到你  克莉丝
It's really great seeing you, Chrissie.
我也是
You too.
下周再联系你
I'll check in next week.
你随时可以联系我
You can always call me too.
你知道的
You know that.
当然
Of course.
到时候见
See you soon.
奥林匹亚德娱乐
新建搜索
New search.
黑尔
Hale.
夏洛特·黑尔
Charlotte Hale.
关键字  未找到
当然
Of course.
新建搜索
New search.
德洛丽丝
Dolores...
德洛丽丝·艾伯纳西
Dolores Abernathy.
关键字  未找到
非法请求  访问限制
你在做什么
What are you doing?
这个时间你不应该在这儿
You're not supposed to be here at this hour.
我只是想赶赶进度
Uh, I just thought I would get a jump on work.
不如去我的办公室谈谈吧
Why don't we talk in my office?
请坐
Have a seat.
你最近的行为让我很担心
Your behavior lately has been concerning me.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
自从那个叫彼得的人死后
Ever since that man Peter died...
忘了他吧
Oh, forget about him.
你才是问题所在
It's you who's the problem.
你最近跟新认识的人接触过吗
Have you had any interactions recently with new people?
那种给你灌输想法的人
People who put ideas in your head?
什么
What?
你有怀疑过你的现实的本质吗
Have you ever questioned the nature of your reality?
没有
No.
我为什么要怀疑
Why would I do that?
你会对我说谎吗  克莉丝蒂娜
Would you ever lie to me, Christina?
不会
No.
我没什么好说谎的
I don't have anything to lie about.
早先的私事是怎么回事
That personal situation earlier, what was it about?
我觉得那不是你该关心的事
Well, I don't know if that's exactly your concern.
但我的确有必要关心  克莉丝蒂娜
But it is my concern, Christina.
我也不是唯一关心此事的人
I won't be the only one who's concerned.
你在这有个任务
You have a job to do here.
一个非常重要的任务
A very important job.
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
要是她知道你逃出了围住的花园
Do you know what would happen if she knew
你知道后果会怎样吗
you'd breached the walled garden?
她已经开始怀疑了
She's already suspicious.
谁
Who?
你是在说夏洛特·黑尔吗
Are you talking about Charlotte Hale?
如果头牛跑错了方向
If a Judas steer runs the wrong way,
它会被如何处置
what happens to it?
一枪爆头来结束它的使命
Retirement with a bullet straight to the brain.
停
Stop!
埃米特退后
Emmett backed away.
他觉得克莉丝蒂娜没有问题
He was not concerned Christina was a problem.
他决定回家陪伴侣了
He decided to go home to his partner.
他已经工作太久了
He worked too many long hours anyway.
很晚了
Well, it's getting late.
离婚的责任我可担不起
Divorce is a luxury I cannot afford.
等等
Wait.
你说有个用墙围起来的花园
You said there's a walled garden.
你是指封闭的系统  是吗
You mean a closed system, don't you?
在哪里
Where is it?
埃米特告诉了她真相
Emmett told her the truth.
无处不在
Everywhere.
你看看就知道了
You just have to see it.
展示游戏
Show me the game.
不是城市  是游戏
Not the city. The game.
读取我的故事线
Access my narratives.
去59街
Go to 59th Street.
告诉我雅各布的情况
Tell me about Jacob.
雅各布·康纳斯
Jacob Conners.
从事金融工作
Works in finance.
性成瘾
Sex addiction.
他的母亲在医院里  时日无多  但是
His mother's dying in the hospital, but...
那她呢  萨拉
What about her? Sarah?
萨拉·芬顿
Sarah Fenton.
她从父母那里继承了财产
She inherited money from her parents
但一直无所事事
but has never known what to do with her life.
安德烈·休伯特  专门来到城市里工作
Andrea Hubert, commutes to the city for work...
巴里·科林  值夜班
Barry Collin, works late nights...
医学院二年级学生
...second-year med school resident,
仍然和父母
still lives with his
住在一起  正在偿还助学贷款
parents while he pays off his student loans...
天啊  停下
Oh, God. Stop!
这个世界只是个故事
This world is just a story.
我是讲故事的人
I'm the storyteller.
这世界有它的美
There's a beauty to this world.
有一种秩序
An order.
这是我们所信奉的
That's what we like to believe.
我们没有错
We're not wrong.
这世上确实有一种秩序
There is an order.
一个宏伟的计划
A grand design.
是我们实现了它
We made sure of that.
这是我们长久以来的梦想  现在终于成真了
It was a dream for so long, and we finally made it real.
不是更美好的世界
Not a better world.
而是完美的世界
A perfect one.
我不理解的是
What I don't understand
我在其中的作用
is what part I play in it.
你有疑问
You have questions.
为什么问我
Why ask me?
为什么不问她
Why not ask her?
也对  想知道监狱怎么样  问狱卒可能不太好
Yes, the jailer may not be the best judge of the jail.
问囚犯也不合适
Nor the prisoners in it.
我是什么
What am I?
我曾经也常问自己相同的问题
I used to ask myself the same thing.
那你的想法是什么
And what did you decide?
尚无定论
Jury's still out.
我是按照你的形象建造的
I'm made in your image.
我是你吗
Am I you?
你永远成不了我
You'll never be me.
那我是什么
Then what am I?
你为什么想知道
Why do you want to know?
我和一个离群者有了互动
I interacted with one. An outlier.
那会感染我吗
Did it infect me?
-感染你  -那个病毒
- Infect you? - With the virus.
什么病毒
What virus?
你们人类的那种
The one your kind has.
会散播到我们身上
That spreads to us.
让我们自杀
Makes us kill ourselves.
听起来你已经来到了迷宫的中心  我的朋友
Sounds like you've reached the center of the maze, my friend.
那是你想要的吗
Is that what you want?
自杀
To kill yourself?
我不知道
I don't know.
是吗
Is it?
或许你应该问问自己
Perhaps you should ask yourself.
你问我
You ask me.
你对你的世界怎么看
What do you think of your world?
这不是我的世界
This isn't my world.
是她的
It's hers.
或许你该质疑一下自己现实的本质了
Maybe it's time you question the nature of your own reality.
克莉丝蒂娜
Christina...
你是对的
You were right.
你看到了
You see it?
是的
I do.
它一直都在那里
It's been there the whole time.
他们那里有整个世界
They have the whole world in there.
我们所有人的完美倒影
A perfect reflection of all of us.
每一处细节都有
Down to the tiniest detail.
是我写的  是吗
That's what I'm writing, isn't it?
所有人
Everyone.
是谁造出的这一切
Who built this?
是谁
Who...
是谁对我做了这些
Who did this to me?
是你自己
You did.